

☑ DruSerkes@gmail.com ② druserkes 203-912-2047 ② New York, NY in dru-serkes druserkes

### **SUMMARY**

Full stack software engineer with a passion for crafting clean code and adhering to DRY principles. Javascript developer with experience building modular, front-end components with React. Former professional Broadway actor of 10 years totaling over 2,300 live performances from New York to Las Vegas. Excellent communicator with over 5 years experience mentoring young artists and athletes in both one-on-one and group settings.

### **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, TypeScript

LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, Flask, jQuery, Jasmine, Jest, React Testing Library, Bootstrap, Material UI

TOOLS: Git, PostgreSQL, Axios, Jinja, VSCode, Heroku, Netlify, AWS

SOFT SKILLS: Public Speaking, Flexibility, Collaboration, Attention to detail

### **EXPERIENCE**

Zephyrx May 2021 - Current

Associate Software Engineer

- Refactored and extended internal tooling to empower clinical trial and customer success departments, reducing ops task workload by 17%
- Improved code quality by implementing GitLab CI pipeline, reducing introduction of test-breaking bugs
- · Worked with clients to address needs, spec requests, and set development roadmap

Technical Engineer, Jr

November 2020 - May 2021

- Added accessibility for 20+ new languages and dialects, resulting in international use of our provider dashboard
- Supported QA team by developing a unit test suite and documentation for our React app, resulting in a single communication close rate over 75%
- Contributed to build stability by coordinating regression testing of web and mobile components, resulting in improved team understanding of product architecture

# Springboard, Software Engineering Career Track Student

April 2020 - September 2020

- 700+ hours of hands-on course material
  - · 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight
  - · Completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects
  - · Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, data structures and algorithms

Jersey Boys Actor · New York, NY August 2015 - March 2020

- Acted in over 1,500 performances of this ubiquitous Broadway Show
- Understudied and carried out the duties of 6 different roles, going on as late as mid-show
- · Took action to save 7,800 ticket refunds over 4 performances by stepping in for duties outside of job scope

King School

January 2020 - March 2020

- Acting Coach · Stamford, CT
  - Advised on best practices for pursuing professional careers in the entertainment industry
  - Offered young professionals modern methods for approaching new and current material
  - Engaged with students of all experience levels one-on-one, producing greater understanding and depth of performance

#### **PROJECTS**

Lyrify 2020

Lyrics for Spotify listeners

- · Crafted a responsive single-page app with React, Redux, and Material UI components working with a Node / Express backend
- Followed Oauth2 protocol for login via Spotify and consumed multiple 3rd party APIs for data aggregation with PostgreSQL
- · Improved MVP by adding custom search feature which validated and cleaned user inputs to increase rate of positive results

Quote Me 2020

React quote generator

- Built and tested responsive single-page app with a combination of React, Typescript, Jest, and Styled Components.
- · MVP consumed a 3rd party API to provide users access to randomly generated quotes they could then copy or Tweet

The Easy Meal 2020

Discover recipes, construct and email yourself a grocery list

- · Built Flask Python backend serving dynamic Jinja HTML templates, and a UI responsively styled with bootstrap and custom CSS
- Secured against CSRF with form validation, and applied bcrypt authentication for user registration and login
- Consumed 3rd party API to access over 380,000 recipes, and cached recipe data with PostgreSQL to reduce API calls.

Mock job-seeking website

2020

- Developed a RESTful API with Node / Express, and a modular UI for this single page React app
- Built and validated forms with Formik and JSONSchema, and managed data with PostgreSQL
- · Followed JWT standard for user authentication and authorization

## **EDUCATION**

Jobly

Springboard 2020 Software Engineering Career Track Certification Emerson College BFA Musical Theatre 2011 Cum Laude. Dean Scholarship Recipient